Guide to the Birge M. Clark Architectural Records and Personal Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Photographs and Slides, Series 2
  - Slides, Subseries 2
    - Henry Barnard (Box 1)
    - Hewlett Packard (Box 1)
    - Hillsdale High School (Box 1)
    - Intermediate School, Mtn. View (Box 1)
    - John Muir, San Jose (Box 1)
    - Jordan Jr. High School (Box 1)
    - Loma Vista Elementary School (Box 2)
    - Los Altos High School (Box 2)
    - Norris Elementary School (Box 2)
    - Ohlones School (Box 2)
    - Ortega School (Box 2)
    - Palo Alto High School (Box 2)
    - Palo Alto - miscellaneous, exhibits (Box 2)
    - Palo Verde School (Box 2)
    - San Carlos school (Box 2)
    - Sterling school (Box 2)
    - Terman Jr. High School (Box 2)
    - Theurkauf (Evans) (Box 2)
    - Van Auken Elementary School (Box 2)
    - Veterans Building (Box 2)
    - Walter Hays School (Box 2)
    - Watkins-Johnson (Box 2)
    - Wilbur Jr. High School (Box 2)
    - Site B and C [possibly Hewlett-Packard site or other Palo Alto industrial park site prior to construction] (Box 2)
    - Corporate Day Care Center - plans (Box 2)
    - Sections - unidentified project (Box 2)
    - Rendering, unidentified (Box 2)
    - Site layout, unidentified (Box 2)
    - Unidentified Group 1 - photos of a school (Box 2)
    - Unidentified Group 2 - aerials of a school (Box 2)
    - Unidentified Group 3 - aerials of a complex, probably a school (Box 2)
    - Unidentified Group 4 - 1 slide of a school (Box 2)
    - Unidentified aerials (Box 2)
    - Unidentified site photos, prior to construction (possibly in Palo Alto) (Box 2)
    - Series on business street signs in Palo Alto (Box 2)
- Specifications, Drawings, and Plans, Series 3
  - Branham High School (Campbell Union High School Districrt), site impact plans, 1989
  - Crittenden Middle School, Mountain View, trellis plan, 1990
  - Alta Mesa Memorial Park, additions, 1936, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Barron Park Elementary School, Palo Alto, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Blackburn Apartment Hotel [President Hotel] Palo Alto, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Boy Scout Fire Circle, Palo Alto, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chadwick Seaside School, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chamberlain, office at residence, Saratoga, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clark (Birge) residence, Edgewood Drive, PA, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Crescent Park Elementary Schoo, Palo Alto, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Gardiner (Gertrude) store, Palo Alto, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hardy (Sumner) resident, guest house, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Medical Offices (Lee, Roth, Clark, Wilbur), 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Menlo School, El Camino dormitory, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Menlo School, group of buildings, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Murphy (Jennie and Bessie) store, Palo Alto, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Norris (Charles) residence, Palo Alto, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Palo Alto Clinic, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Palo Alto Community Auditorium and Theater, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Palo Alto Community Center, Ruth Stern Wing, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Palo Alto School District, South Palo Alto school building, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Palo Alto Senior High, boys gym, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Palo Alto Times, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pease (Howard) residence, Palo Alto, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - San Carlos fire house, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Seaside School Corporation, residence, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stern (Mrs. Louis), two residences, Palo Alto, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Walter Hays School, Palo Alto, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Waterhouse residence [consists of editorial changes to specs for Saier residence], 1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Whiting (H.S.) residence, Saratoga, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Wideman and Son store, Palo Alto, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Byxbee and Jackson store, Palo Alto, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cardinal Hotel [Palo Alto Hotel Improvement Co.], undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Castilleja School addition, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Clark (Birge) residence, Webster and Embarcadero, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dunker (John) residence, Palo Alto, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Enderson (A. L.) residence, Palo Alto, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Frier (W. L.) residence, Menlo Park, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Hare, Brewer and Clark store building, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hoover residence, Stanford campus, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Kee (Leung) restaurant, Palo Alto, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Lockey (Richard) residence, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Masonic Temple Association, store and banquet hall, Palo Alto, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Menlo School, dormitory and class building, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Norris (Charles), Saratoga pool, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Norris (Charles) residence, Palo Alto, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Palo Alto Fire and Police Station, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Palo Alto High School, additions, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Palo Alto High School gym, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Palo Alto Improvement Co. (stores on Ramona Street), 1927 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Palo Alto School District, Addison Avenue School, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Palo Alto School District, South Palo Alto school, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Post Office, Palo Alto, circa 1930 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Post Office, Palo Alto, circa 1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Professional building, Palo Alto, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Quinby (James) residence, Palo Alto, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ramona Street stores (Lansdale and Thoits), 1926 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Thoits store, University Avenue, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Townley (S. D.) residence, Stanford, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - University Realty Company store building, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Van Heusden (Karel) residence, Atherton, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Varsity Theater remodel, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Walter Hays School, Palo Alto, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Boy and Girl Scout Center, negative of site plan (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cal-West Communities, site plan transparencies, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cal-West Communities, building types transparencies, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cal-West Communities, positive prints of plans, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cal-West Communities, Sunnyvale, photos of renderings, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cal-West Communities, Sunset Park of Marin, transparencies, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Clark, David B., photos of drawings for Columbia University class (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cubberley High School, transparency of bird's eye rendering (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fairfield Senior Center, printing negative of proposed site plan (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fleishhacker residence, Western Homes Competition, plans (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Hewlett Packard, Bay Region Honor Awards Program, plans and descriptive data, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hewlett Packard, Boise, Idaho, model for (slides and prints) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Hoover, Lou Henry, House, plans (negs and prints) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Housing compound, unidentified (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Mountain View Senior Center, plans (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Mountain View Senior Center, plan negs (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Palo Alto Community Center, printing neg and positive print (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Palo Alto Post Office, photo of rendering (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Palo Alto Senior Center (former Police Dept.), elevations, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Palo Alto YMCA, plans, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - President Hotel, Palo Alto, photo of typical floor plan (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Ramona Street Stores, Palo Alto, photo of rendering, circa 1935 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - San Jose Civic Center, negs and 1 print of master plan (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Seeley G. Mudd Chemistry Building, Stanford University, photos of renderings and booklet, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Stanford University Medical School (S. F.), Stern research lab, negs of plan and rendering, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Stauffer Chemistry Buildings, Stanford University, plans and dedication booklet, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Strub, Dr. Chas., group of stores on University Avenue, P.A., photo of elevation (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Syntex Laboratories, photos of elevations and annual report, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Terman Junior High School, P.A., negs and prints of plans, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Wells Fargo Bank, Sunnyvale, plans and elevations (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Ames Research Center, plans and 1 negative, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cal-West Communties, building types, negatives (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cal-West Communties, Sunset Oaks and Sunset Park I, negatives of plans (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hewlett Packard, A.I.A. National Awards Program, plans (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Five Hoover houses (1 plan, 1 plot layout) and Stern residence (patterns for tile bench in garden) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Jordan Jr. High School, 1 floor plan for health department, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Mountain View Senior Center, 1 printing negative (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Palo Alto Community Theater, stage board and wiring diagram (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Syntex Laboratories, printing negative of rendering (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Wells Fargo, Sunnyvale, 2 color photos of renderings (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Whisman Sports Center, drawings on tissue (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Course Files and Other Files, Series 4
  - School building inspection course, CA Dept. of Public Works, correspondence and lecture text, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford classes, correspondence, 1950-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arch 148, tests, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arch 248, examinations, 1953-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arch 251, examinations and comments on exam, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arch 274D, summary, exams, review items, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arch 285B, final exam, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arch 286, syllabus, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arch 286, syllabus, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arch 386, syllabus, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arch 386, exams, review points, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Class materials - millwork information, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Class materials - paint information (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Class materials, 1960-61 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Class materials assorted, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Course materials, "John Doe" specifications, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lecture on buying a house (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lecture, "Materials and their specification,", 1972 Mar (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University Class of 1914, correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University Class of 1914, correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Stanford University Class of 1914, fundraising instructions, forms, etc., 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Friends of France, American Ambulance Field Service, Stanford University, list of survivors and deceased (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Memoirs - An Architect Grows up in Palo Alto, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - World War I Memoirs, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Clippings on Birge Clark, 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Address book (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Birge M. Clark Day," Palo Alto, 1984 Jun 5 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Dirty Old Men Can Putt Too," article by D.O.M. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Fremont Post 52, American Legion, clippings and biographical histories, 1919 and 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Genealogy, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lucie Stern, clippings about, 1940-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Kiwanis Club of Palo Alto, Roster, 1972 Jan (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Institute of Architects, certificates of honor, 1929-1935 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Resolution ... Proclaiming June 5, 1984, "Birge M. Clark Day," (Box 3)
  - Master of Architecture diploma, Columbia University, 1917 (Box 3)
  - Annual of the School of Architecture, Columbia University, to Cover the Work of the Year 1917, 1918 (Box 3)
  - Yosemite Summary of the Draft General Management Plan, with hand-drawn map inside front cover, 1978 Aug (Box 3)
  - Plaque mounted on wood: Presented by the Stanford School of Engineering to Birge M. Clark to Honor His contribution as a Member of the Faculty 1950-1972 (Box 4)
  - Class roll books from SU classes; filed with other SC restricted folders